<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>WT2 WS 2019/20 on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/wt2-usability/assignments/</link><description>Recent content in WT2 WS 2019/20 on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/wt2-usability/assignments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Assignment 01</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/wt2-usability/assignments/assignment_01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/wt2-usability/assignments/assignment_01/</guid><description>Heuristical Analysis of Example Application, Topic Definition E-Learning: Usability Heuristics This is not part of the Assignment 01 per se, but needs to be done as a preparation.
We got a rough overview of Nielsen&amp;rsquo;s 10 Usability Heuristics in class. Your e-learning assignment is to study all of them and write a short summary (2-3 pages). This should be done individually, as preparation for the group work.
Read these articles, summarize them and upload your summary to moodle:</description></item><item><title>Assignment 02</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/wt2-usability/assignments/assignment_02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/wt2-usability/assignments/assignment_02/</guid><description>User Research: Contextual Interviews and Personas Interviews Conduct Contextual Interviews. Each person in the team should conduct one Interview of about an hour.
Interpretation Sessions You conduct one interpretation session for each interview. The whole team participates in the interpretation session! You&amp;rsquo;ll probably need more time than just the time in the lab for the interpretation sessions.
Affinity Create an Affinity Diagram.
Personas Define Personas as described in Chapter 3 in Cooper: About Face.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 03</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/wt2-usability/assignments/assignment_03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/wt2-usability/assignments/assignment_03/</guid><description>Design and Evaluation I: Visioning, Product Concepts and Storyboards Visioning Start with creating (or completing) the three input lists:
hot ideas issues technology Create 4-7 Visions Start the visions from hot ideas. Assign the roles
Pen Poker Team And alternate them between the visions such that each of you gets to practice each role. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a Flipchart available, use a A3-Paper in the middle of the table.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 04</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/wt2-usability/assignments/assignment_04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/wt2-usability/assignments/assignment_04/</guid><description>Design and Evaluation II: Paper Prototypes Paper Prototypes Create two Paper Prototypes per Team based on two of your Storyboards.
Choose the Stories / Storyboards carefully, and document the reasons for your decision in your report.
You can both work together on both storyboards or have two teams of two working on one Paper Prototype each.
Paper Prototype Evaluation Now, you have to get together with your expert team again, preferably during the lab sessions:</description></item></channel></rss>