<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Info2 SoSe 2020 - Labs and Exercises on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/</link><description>Recent content in Info2 SoSe 2020 - Labs and Exercises on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Info2: Exercise 00:</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-14/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Assignment Lab Report / What to turn in Your report is due the day before your next lab (for exact times, please refer to moodle).
Submit a Report in PDF Format and the Source Code as Zipped file.
As in Informatics 1, I am more interested in process than in product, although we are now getting more interested in products as well. Your report should include any collaborators on top of the first page, summarize what you learned, and note the time you invested in this exercise.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 01: Application Design</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-01/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Remember to do all the necessary steps listed on the Labs page, including the following exercises:
P1. How do you obtain tickets to go see a movie? Write down the steps that you take, in order.
P2. If you have tickets and have to cancel, what do you have to do? Write down the steps, in order.
P3. Find out what the Class-Responsibility-Collaboration Card method is, what the use of CRC Cards is and how they are created.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 02: Implementing CRC Cards</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-02/</guid><description>Pre-Lab This exercise builds on the design you did last week using CRC cards. Please think through the following questions together with your team before coming to the lab and write down your answers somewhere.
P1. What properties should a data structure have that can model movie theater seats?
P2. Given an n x m matrix and a cell c in (r, c). How do I reference the neighboring cells in the same row?</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 03: Histogram</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-03/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Please think through the following questions before coming to the lab. Write down your answers and be prepared to answer them in class.
P1. In some programming languages, such as Ada, you can define an array of characters with any discrete type as the index:
someArray : ARRAY ['A' .. 'Z'] of INTEGER; You can then access the array, for example, using a value of character type: someArray[&amp;lsquo;T&amp;rsquo;]. Java does not have this feature.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 04: Chatterbox</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-04/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Write down the code for the following questions and be able to explain what is happening.
P1. How do you set up a connection with Sockets between two computers in Java?
P2. Write a method to read from a connection in Java.
P3. Write a method to write to a connection in Java.
P4. How do you create concurrent threads?
Assignment Step 1: Client sends messages to Server Start your chatterbox by writing a method that listens for a Socket connection on a port.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 05: Execution times</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-05/</guid><description>Pre-Lab P1. Programs A and B are analyzed and are found to have worst-case running times no greater than 150 N log N and N2, respectively. Answer the following questions, if possible:
a) Which program has the better guarantee on the running time for large values of N (N &amp;gt; 10 000)?
b) Which program has the better guarantee on the running time for small values of N (N &amp;lt; 100)?</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 06: Reverse Polish Notation</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-06/</guid><description>Pre-Lab P1. Make sure that you understand postfix evaluation. If you do the complete Pre-Lab you will be able to understand the algorithms given in the hand out.
P2. What is the order of precedence for the operators &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;-&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;*&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;/&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;^&amp;rdquo;? If we wanted to include &amp;ldquo;(&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;)&amp;rdquo; in this order, where would each of them be?
P3. Łukasiewicz was a Polish logician, so his notation for parentheses-free expressions is often called Reverse Polish Notation.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 07: Recursive Triangles</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-07/</guid><description>Pre-Lab P1. What exactly is an equilateral triangle? Can you write a class that draws a triangle? What data do you need to know in order to put a triangle at a particular position on the screen?
P2. What is the mathematical formula for finding the midpoint of a line segment that connects two Points?
P3. What is the resolution of your computer screen? How can you find out? What is the largest equilateral triangle that you can show on a screen with this resolution?</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 08: Eight Queens</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-08/</guid><description>Pre-Lab P1. Make a chess board and mark how a Queen moves and threatens.
P2. Define a matrix (two-dimensional array) of integers in Java. Write a method to put a -1 in every cell of the matrix.
P3. Given two cells in a matrix, (r1, c1) and (r2, c2). How can you determine if a) the cells are in the same row? b) the cells are in the same column? c) the cells are in the same ascending diagonal (lower left to upper right)?</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 08: Multi-Threaded Chat Application</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-08-chat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-08-chat/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Experiment with the Source Code Examples for Concurrency.
Do a Class Design for your Chat Application: Don&amp;rsquo;t put all of the Server in one and all of the Client in another class; design small classes with one responsibility and small methods. Especially the user interface should not be intermingled with the rest of the application.
Assignment: Multi-Threaded Chat This builds on Assignment 3, Chatterbox, where you built a little Chat Application that was only able to handle one connection from one client.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 09: Probabilistic Algorithms</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-09/</guid><description>Pre-Lab P1. How do you compute the area of a circle and a rectangle?
P2. Draw an circle that matches exactly into a square. How do the areas of the circle and the square relate to each other?
P3. How can you represent points in a plane?
P4. Prepare a sketch with formulas about the ratio of the areas and how to determine if a given point in the square is as well within the circle.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 10: Getting from A to B</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-10/</guid><description>S-Bahn Ring generated with https://github.com/bkleinen/bvg-graph based on OpenStreetMap
Pre-Lab P1. Define an interface data type for a weighted graph. What methods does it need? What are the signatures?
P2. Read on Depth-First-Search and Dijkstra Algorithm to compute the shortest and cheapest path in a given graph. We&amp;rsquo;ve covered them in class, also.
P3. Your algorithm will probably need an adjacency matrix oder an adjacency list as its data structure. Think about how you would implement such a structure, if you only had linked lists available.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 11: Finite State Automata and Sorting Algorithms</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-11/</guid><description>Pre-Lab P1. What is the difference between an NFA and an DFA?
P2. Which sorting algorithms have you learned about so far? Review their algorithms.
Geeks for Geeks has some helpful explanations, including nice videos. Useful for a quick reminder of the algorithms. Eg. Selection Sort.
Really good more detailed explanations can be found at the Back to Back SWE YouTube Channel:
Insertion Sort Merge Sort Quick Sort Heap Sort Assignment Part 1: Finite Automata This is to get some practice with Finite Automata.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 12: Scrabble Cheater - Basic Edition</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-12/</guid><description>Foto by Mags_cat
Pre-Lab P1. Review the rules of Scrabble, if you have never played it before.
P2. What is a permutation?
P3. What would a normalization function for different permutations of words look like? That is, &amp;ldquo;JAVA&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;VAJA&amp;rdquo; are permutations, what would a normalized permutation look like?
P4. How do you determine if two Strings are permutations of each other?
P5. For the bored: How can you generate all permutations of the characters in a String?</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 13: Scrabble Cheater - Deluxe</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-13/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Foto by Piotr
What would the exact data structure be for a hash table that stores Strings and chains the collisions? Review the construction of a hash function. Note that you will need prime numbers. Does your isPrime method work? If not, fix it now. Assignment This week we will improve the Scrabble Cheater by finding matches for shorter Words that can be build with your tile rack (method allValidWords()).</description></item><item><title>Info2: Handout for Exercise 6: Infix/Prefix/Postfix</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-06-handout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2020/info2/labs/lab-06-handout/</guid><description>Definitions Infix: The operator is placed between the two operands: 3 + 5
Prefix: The operator is placed before the two operands: + 3 5
Postfix: The operator is placed after the two operands: 3 5 +
Calculator algorithm Convert infix to postfix Use stack to evaluate postfix Output top of stack (should be the only element) Convert infix to postfix algorithm Given a sequence of tokens s and a result r While s is not empty: Let t = next token.</description></item></channel></rss>