<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Info1 - Labs and Exercises on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2022/info1/labs/</link><description>Recent content in Info1 - Labs and Exercises on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2022/info1/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exercise 00: Lab Startup</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2022/info1/labs/exercise-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2022/info1/labs/exercise-00/</guid><description>Source code for this exercise: https://github.com/htw-imi-info1/kara
Welcome to the laboratory - that&amp;rsquo;s what we call these rooms filled with computer equipment. We have lots of rules for the labs, as they are used by many different people during the week. You find a link to the rules (&amp;ldquo;Laborordnung&amp;rdquo;) here.
Two really important rules are:
No food. We don&amp;rsquo;t like crumbs in the keyboards. Drinks are okay if they are in a container with a screw-on lid and the lid is screwed on.</description></item><item><title>Exercise 01: Programming Kara</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2022/info1/labs/exercise-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2022/info1/labs/exercise-01/</guid><description>Source code for this exercise: https://github.com/htw-imi-info1/exercise01-kara
Pre-Lab Download the Scenarios and read through the Kara programming exercises in the assignment.
Write down how Kara could solve the task for each one of them. For example, if the programming exercise was Exercise 4 from Worksheet 1, where Kara was to move in a Square and drop a leaf in each corner, you could write down something as this:</description></item><item><title>Exercise 02: TicketMachine</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2022/info1/labs/exercise-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2022/info1/labs/exercise-02/</guid><description>Printed Ticket. Sludge GSource code for this exercise: https://github.com/htw-imi-info1/exercise02
Pre-lab 0. What could be wrong with the following constructor? Don&amp;rsquo;t execute it, think about it in your head.
public TicketMachine (int ticketCost) { int price = ticketCost; balance = 0; total = 0; } 1. How can you tell the difference between a method and a constructor just by looking at its header?
2. What do you think would be printed if you altered the fourth statement of printTicket so that price also has quotes around it, as follows: System.</description></item></channel></rss>