<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Example Project for Web Technology on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/example-project/</link><description>Recent content in Example Project for Web Technology on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/example-project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Example Project for Web Technology - Week 2</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/example-project/week-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/example-project/week-2/</guid><description>Week 2 - Active Record Associations, Migrations and Views Example Project on GitHub 1. Pick a story that requires you to introduce at least one new Resource to your Project. I pick:
When the user clicks on a habit, it can be edited. A log of dates when the habit was performed is shown. This requires the Log to be stored in a separte entity, one LogEntry for each time the Habit has been completed, connected with a belongs_to has_many (1:n) association.</description></item><item><title>Example Project for Web Technology - Week 3</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/example-project/week-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/example-project/week-3/</guid><description>Week 3 Example Project on GitHub Testing, Setting up a Deployment Workflow, and some Ruby 1. Create at least one happy-path feature test for each person on your team. Use Capybara. I demonstrate this on the story
A user kann log an habit as completed on that day by simply clicking on a button in the habit list. Before I start working on that, I should clean up the generated tests and create some test data for the Habits.</description></item><item><title>Example Project for Web Technology - Week 4</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/example-project/week-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/example-project/week-4/</guid><description>Week 4 For this week, we&amp;rsquo;ll use another example project. I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce it in class, but have a look at the readme to get an Idea what it is about: Example Project for Week 4 on GitHub
Authentication 1. Add a user model and set it up with encrypted password If you don&amp;rsquo;t already have a user model, create one:
rails g scaffold User name:string password:digest if you already have a user model (it may have another name), make sure it has a field for password.</description></item><item><title>Example Project for Web Technology - Week 5</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/example-project/week-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/example-project/week-5/</guid><description>Week 5 Example Project for this week: Example Project for Week 5 on GitHub: Notebook
It&amp;rsquo;s just an app with one resource, Note, which has one attribute, content.
I used JavaScript to add Notes on the notes#index page without reloading the page, following the example &amp;ldquo;A Simple Example&amp;rdquo; in the Rails Guides on AJAX.
This is the commit where I added the changes described in the tutorial.</description></item></channel></rss>