<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Info3/SS2013 - Labs and Exercises on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/</link><description>Recent content in Info3/SS2013 - Labs and Exercises on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/tech-stuff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/tech-stuff/</guid><description>Which Computer to use? As most of your colleagues in the former semesters completely ignored the new iMacs in our Web Technology lab and rather unfolded their old, dirty little subnotebooks in front of the 27&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; screens (which even cannot be used as an external monitor), I expect that you will also mainly use your personal computers for working on the exercises. If doing so, you need to make sure to have a set of software available.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 02 - Use Cases and Class Diagrams</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-02/</guid><description>In this exercise you will create a description, develop a detailed Scenario for a Use Case, and draw a Class Diagram for an application called &amp;ldquo;HTW&amp;rdquo; - Halloween Treats Worldwide.
First, have a look at the description of the system:
Halloween Treats Worldwide Foto by Pedro J. Ferreira
Halloween Treats Worldwide (HTW) is planned to be an online-shop where people can buy original Halloween Treats. The product manager has asked you to design and develop the platform for their business.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 03 - Gilded Rose Patterns and Sequence Diagrams</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-03a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-03a/</guid><description>Reading Assignment for Friday, May 3rd 2013: For this week&amp;rsquo;s lecture and especially the exercise, you will need some knowledge about sequence diagrams, and the Patterns Strategy, Factory, Factory method, Abstract Factory and Template Method.
Here are some good sources:
Sequence Diagrams: Sample Chapter from Fowler&amp;rsquo;s UML distilled: https://www.informit.com/articles/article.aspx?p=169507&amp;amp;seqNum=2 - Please read the full chapter. Strategy Pattern: - make sure you understand the pattern. Template Method: we talked about that in class (Sandy Metz Ruby example!</description></item><item><title>Assignment 03 - GIT and State Machine Diagrams</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-03/</guid><description>Foto by Jeff Kubina
Pre-Lab Git &amp;amp; GitHub Git is the state-of-the-art Source Code Management Tool. Install the command line client for your platform, and maybe also a GUI Client, which can all be found here. Sign up on GitHub if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already done so. See also Setting up Git from GitHub for a comprehensive documentation. For other projects, you might want to use the HTW Projekteserver which offers you private repositorys, or any other service offering central repositories.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 1: Testing</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/assignment-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/assignment-01/</guid><description>A. Test Driven Development Create a new Java Project in Eclipse (or your preferred IDE).
Source Code for this Assignment: (removed)
Create a Class Node as in Node.java _as Head of a linked list (added 5.4.13) _and develop a method for deleting Nodes in a List test driven, that is, develop the Unit Tests first, as we did in class. Choose one of the two methods we discussed in class to help the assertions - creating a test helper method as in assert.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 1: Testing</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-01/</guid><description>A. Test Driven Development Create a new Java Project in Eclipse (or your preferred IDE).
Source Code for this Assignment: (removed)
Create a Class Node as in Node.java as Head of a linked list and develop a method for deleting Nodes in a List test driven, that is, develop the Unit Tests first, as we did in class. Choose one of the two methods we discussed in class to help the assertions - creating a test helper method as in assert.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 4: First Rails Steps</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-004/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-004/</guid><description>In this exercise, you will create a rails application for the first one or two features / user stories of your application. Pick one simple thing that you can solve mainly with the provided CRUD (Create Read Update Delete) features of a rails scaffold using just one or two model classes. If the first things seems to simple for that, add a second – but the goal is really to implement just a little bit of functionality in this first step and mainly set up the whole rails app together with Continuous Integration – we will add Continuous Deployment in the next exercise.</description></item><item><title>Exercise 05 - Sequence Diagrams and Ruby Finger Exercises</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-05/</guid><description>Part 1: Sequence Diagrams Pelican launch sequence. Foto by Don McCullough Prelab Martin Fowler&amp;rsquo;s Chapter about Sequence Diagrams from the book &amp;ldquo;UML Distilled&amp;rdquo; is available as a sample chapter online.
Read it as a preparation for the lab.
Assignment As a finger exercise for Sequence Diagrams, pick one of the following example projects from the first semester and draw a sequence diagram for the main use case:
The Clock Display / Use case: timeTick() is called Auction / Use case: makeABid() is called Tech Support / Use case: user command is entered (start() method in SupportSystem) The Zuul Project / Use case: user enters command (method: play() in Game.</description></item><item><title>Exercise 05 - UML Part IV: Sequence Diagrams</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-05a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-05a/</guid><description>Pelican launch sequence. Foto by Don McCullough Prelab Martin Fowler&amp;rsquo;s Chapter about Sequence Diagrams from the book &amp;ldquo;UML Distilled&amp;rdquo; is available as a sample chapter online.
Read it as a preparation for the lab.
Assignment As a finger exercise for Sequence Diagrams, pick one of the following example projects from the first semester and draw a sequence diagram for the main use case:
The Clock Display / Use case: timeTick() is called Auction / Use case: makeABid() is called Tech Support / Use case: user command is entered (start() method in SupportSystem) The Zuul Project / Use case: user enters command (method: play() in Game.</description></item><item><title>Exercise 06 - Rails - First Steps</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-06/</guid><description>Foto by Pedro J. Ferreira
Prelab Read through two Rails Guides: https://guides.rubyonrails.org/active_record_basics.html https://guides.rubyonrails.org/association_basics.html Assignment Part 0: On the order#show page, show the associated customer with its name rather than the ID - Test driven! You can use the :order1 factory for this, see Part 1 for more info on FactoryGirl test data.
Part 1: Creating Testdata You should never be attached to manually created test data living in your development or test database.</description></item><item><title>Exercise 07 - Internationalization, n:m Associations and a Bit of Functionality</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-07/</guid><description>Assignment Sort or Search Pumpkins On the Pumpkin index site, add either a sort function for at least one pumpkin attribute or a search functionality. You will need to add a link or form to the index site, and perform the ordering/searching from the controller altering the @pumpkins variable. [https://guides.rubyonrails.org/active_record_querying.html] (https://guides.rubyonrails.org/active_record_querying.html) contains all necessary information on how to query Pumpkins.
*** remember to make use of all the great pumpkins all of you added with their pull request you can use to populate your database!</description></item><item><title>Lab 04 - Legacy Code - Refactoring to Patterns</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info3/labs/lab-04/</guid><description>The Gilded Rose, Trade District, World of Warcraft.
Assignment: Gilded Rose Kata Source Code: There are three versions. Choose one. Have brief look at the readme and the GuildedRose class.
Ruby Version: https://github.com/htw-imi-info3-archive/gilded-rose-kata Java/Eclipse Version with Test Stub: https://github.com/htw-imi-info3-archive/lab-05-JavaMavenGildedRoseJavaEclipse Original Version using Maven: https://github.com/htw-imi-info3-archive/lab-05-JavaMavenGildedRose Write Characterization Tests To be able to add the new functionality as requested you should write Characterization tests first. You will not yet refactor or add the required new functionality!</description></item></channel></rss>