<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Info3 - Labs and Exercises on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/</link><description>Recent content in Info3 - Labs and Exercises on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/labs-notes-fuer-naechstes-mal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/labs-notes-fuer-naechstes-mal/</guid><description>in lab01 klar schreiben ob source code mit abgegeben werden soll oder nicht</description></item><item><title>Assignment 02 - Use Cases and Class Diagrams</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-02-usecases-class/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-02-usecases-class/</guid><description>The Art and Science of Diagramming. Foto by Gary Barber
Pre-Lab 1. Know what the lab is about In this exercise you will develop a detailed Scenario for a Use Case, and draw a Class Diagram for an application called &amp;ldquo;HTW&amp;rdquo; - Halloween Treats Worldwide. Have a look at the description of the system:
Halloween Treats Worldwide Foto by Pedro J. Ferreira
Halloween Treats Worldwide (HTW) is planned to be an online-shop where people can buy original Halloween Treats.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 03 - Sequence Diagrams and State Machine Diagrams</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-03-sequence-state/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-03-sequence-state/</guid><description>Pelican launch sequence. Foto by Don McCullough Pre-Lab Read Martin Fowler&amp;rsquo;s Chapter about Sequence Diagrams from the book &amp;ldquo;UML Distilled&amp;rdquo; is available as a sample chapter online. For an introduction to state machine diagrams, see https://www.agilemodeling.com/artifacts/stateMachineDiagram.htm. Assignment Part 1: Sequence Diagrams As a finger exercise for Sequence Diagrams, pick one of the following example projects from the first semester and draw a sequence diagram for the main use case: The Clock Display / Use case: timeTick() is called Tech Support / Use case: user command is entered (start() method in SupportSystem) The Zuul Project / Use case: user enters command (method: play() in Game.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 04: Testing</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-04-testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-04-testing/</guid><description>Test Button in Car. Foto by Mike Roberts
Assignment Preparation Download the source code snippets for this assignment: lab04-testing Prepare your project like we did it in the first lab (Part 1: Set up the git repository and project). Note that this is now lab04, so make sure you adapt your process to that! Eg. put the project into the correct place on the gitlab server. In addition to what you&amp;rsquo;ve covered in class, please have a look at black-box and white-box testing.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 05 - Legacy Code - Refactoring to Patterns</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-05-legacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-05-legacy/</guid><description>The Gilded Rose, Trade District, World of Warcraft.
Assignment: Gilded Rose Kata Preparation Clone the Gilded Rose Repository. Set up the project like we did it in the first lab (Part 1: Set up the git repository and project). Of course this is now lab05, put your project into the correct place on the gitlab server! Hint: If you like you can use WebStorm and it&amp;rsquo;s automatic refactoring features. You can get an educational license.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 06 - Rails - First Steps</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-06-rails-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-06-rails-1/</guid><description>Foto by Pedro J. Ferreira
Revised - without significant changes to the assignment itself except taking out Factory Girl/Bot - on 1/1/18. If you&amp;rsquo;ve started working on this assignment before, you can view the changes in the commit &amp;ldquo;info3 - revised lab 06&amp;rdquo; on bkleinen.github.io
Prelab The Base Repo (referred to as main repository below) for this Lab is the HTW Application we&amp;rsquo;ve developed in class, see https://github.com/htw-imi-info3-archive/rails-dash-ws2017 - first fork it on github (only one person in your team needs to do this) and then clone it to your local workspace (computer).</description></item><item><title>Assignment 06 - Web Apps with Node and Express I</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-06-express-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-06-express-1/</guid><description>Overview In the course of this and the following Lab Assignment, you will implement a rudimentary web application based on node and express.js.
The goal of the exercises is gain first experiences with fundamental steps of web application development, rather than completing the app!
In the end, your app is expected to have the following features:
Lab 06 - Express 1 contain at least 1 view template displaying data that is hard-coded in the controller process parameters sent from an HTML form in the controller MVC: View and Controller should be clearly separated, e.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 07 - Search &amp; Sort, Internationalization</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-07-rails-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-07-rails-2/</guid><description>Assignment Part 1: Add a Sort or Search Functionality Each Group should add a sort or search functionality to one of the resources pages of the HTW app. We will coordinate the tasks using issues on the repository, see https://github.com/htw-imi-info3-archive/rails-dash-ws2017/issues, and also coordinate within the lab.
See the Guide on the Active Record Query Interface - it contains all necessary information on how to query and sort Pumpkins and other stuff.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 07 - Web Apps with Node and Express II</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-07-express-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-07-express-2/</guid><description>Example apps: App 03 - Persistence and App 04 - with testing
(This builds on app02)
From Lab06 to Lab07 You will continue working on your project from Lab06. However, it should be in a separate code base. So you should create a new empty repository on GitLab in the folder for Lab07 and add this new repo as the new origin of your local repository. For Lab07, only push to the project in the Lab07 folder!</description></item><item><title>Assignment 07 - Web Apps with Node and Express II</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-08-express-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-08-express-3/</guid><description>From Lab07 to Lab08 You will continue working on your project from Lab07. However, it should be in a separate code base. So you should create a new empty repository on GitLab in the folder for Lab08 and add this new repo as the new origin of your local repository. For Lab08, only push to the project in the Lab08 folder!
Assignment 1: Clean Up a) Check the requirements Check the following questions and if the answer is no, fix it.</description></item><item><title>Exercise 01 - Case Studies of Ethical Questions</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-01-casestudies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-01-casestudies/</guid><description>The German &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Gesellschaft für Informatik&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; published Ethical Guidelines in 1994 that were updated in 2004. They are available online at https://fg-ie.gi.de/ethische-leitlinien.html.
We will first have a closer look at the Ethical Guidelines, and then in groups of 3-4 persons you will choose one of the scenarios to read, discuss, and present to the class. Every member of the group will submit their own PDF version with a reflection on the scenario and how the Ethical Guidelines apply to this case.</description></item><item><title>Exercise 01 - Installation Instructions</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-01-startup-installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-01-startup-installation/</guid><description>(These are detailled instructions for the installation part of the Info 3 Startup Lab).
Which Computer to use? As most of your colleagues in the former semesters completely ignored the new iMacs in our Web Technology lab and rather unfolded tiny notebooks in front of the 27&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; screens (which unfortunatley even cannot be used as an external monitor), I expect that you will also mainly use your personal computers for working on the exercises.</description></item><item><title>Exercise 01 - Lab Startup and JavaScript Finger Exercises</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-01-startup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2020/info3/labs/lab-01-startup/</guid><description>Nerd Workplace. Foto by slworking2
Pre-Lab (Do this BEFORE the lab) 1. Prepare your work environment The labs will be taught remote. You can either
work on the lab computers from remote (make sure to chose the lab that is given on your schedule) or just work on your own computer. If you decide to work on your own computer:
[optional] I recomment you work on a Linux or MacOS System.</description></item></channel></rss>