<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Info 2 WS 2021/22 - Labs and Exercises on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/info2/labs/</link><description>Recent content in Info 2 WS 2021/22 - Labs and Exercises on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/info2/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Info2: Exercise 00: Programming &amp; Tools</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/info2/labs/lab-00/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/info2/labs/lab-00/</guid><description>Pre-Lab (Do this BEFORE the lab) 1. Prepare your work environment The labs will be taught on campus. You can either
work on a lab computer or work on the lab computers from remote (make sure to chose the lab that is given on your schedule) or just work on your own laptop that you bring to class If you decide to work on your own computer:
Install and set up git (You will use git to hand in code - you will be added to the Info2 group when you get added on Moodle).</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 01: Application Design</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/info2/labs/lab-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/info2/labs/lab-01/</guid><description>CRC Cards
Pre-Lab Remember to do all the necessary steps listed on the Labs page, including the following exercises:
P1. Refamiliarize yourself with the Zuul Project in Info1.
P2. Recall the Responsibilities of the given classes. What was the point of the refactoring(s)?
P3. Find out what the Class-Responsibility-Collaboration Card method is, what the use of CRC Cards is and how they are created. The following resources can be of help:</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 02: Implementing CRC Cards</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/info2/labs/lab-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/info2/labs/lab-02/</guid><description>Pre-Lab This exercise builds on the design you did last week using CRC cards. Please think through the following questions together with your team before coming to the lab and write down your answers somewhere.
P1. What part of the data do you need to save in order to persist the game status for one player?
P2. Re-consider your CRC cards and sort the requirements in sections that should be implemented together, e.</description></item></channel></rss>