<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Assignments for Web Technology on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/</link><description>Recent content in Assignments for Web Technology on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/week-1-takeouts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/week-1-takeouts/</guid><description>https://github.com/htw-imi-m1-ss2017/ruby-learning
Working on your project Write down your project vision. Write down your product backlog. Roughly prioritize it for business value. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to write down as many stories as you want, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to implement them all. Pick a user story that you can implement with simple CRUD operations. Draw a scribble for the screens involved. Draw a first sketch of the data model that is suffient for this story.</description></item><item><title>Example Project for Web Technology - Week 4</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/week-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/week-4/</guid><description> nothing here yet</description></item><item><title>Example Project for Web Technology - Week 5</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/week-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/week-5/</guid><description> nothing here yet</description></item><item><title>Week 1 - First Steps in Ruby and Ruby on Rails</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/week-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/week-1/</guid><description>Overview install ruby and ruby on rails contribute to the ruby-learning project create a project vision and backlog work through the &amp;ldquo;getting started with rails&amp;rdquo;-guide 0. Install Ruby and Ruby on Rails There are hints for installtation in the Getting Started with Rails Guide linked below.
1. contribute to the ruby-learning project In class, we will / did start a project to learn about ruby: https://github.com/htw-imi-m1-ss2017/ruby-learning
Finish one topic per person.</description></item><item><title>Week 2 - Active Record Associations, Migrations and Views</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/week-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/week-2/</guid><description>Week 2 ongoing: Contribute to the Ruby-Learning project If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, contribute to the ruby learning project:
https://github.com/htw-imi-m1-ss2017/ruby-learning
Finish one topic per person. Please send me your github login to add you as a contributor for the project.
Active Record Associations, Migrations and Views Reading and preparation You should have enough background information for working on this week&amp;rsquo;s assignment based on the Getting started with Rails you worked through last week.</description></item><item><title>Week 3 - Testing, CI and CD</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/week-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/week-3/</guid><description>Week 3 Reading In week 3, we&amp;rsquo;ll work on Rails Testing. Please read through the Rails Testing Guide and have a look at the Capybara DSL which we will use to write end-to-end feature tests.
A Guide to Testing Rails Applications Capybara&amp;rsquo;s DSL Also, we&amp;rsquo;ll set up continuous integration and continuous deployment using the services travis and heroku respectively.
Travis for Ruby Rails 5 on Heroku Background Martin Fowler: Continuous Integration Continuous Integration - The digest on the Thoughtworks Page Testing, Setting up a Deployment Workflow, and some Ruby Working on your project again, see the example project for clarification on what to do.</description></item><item><title>Week 4&amp;5 - Login and AJAX</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/week-4-5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2017/media-programming-rails/assignments/week-4-5/</guid><description>In the last two weeks, you will add a simple login-mechanism and add a bit of JavaScript.
Reading For next week, read about rolling your own authentication in rails:
Michael Hartl&amp;rsquo;s Rails Tutorial Chapter 8 Alternatively, you can decide to use a third-party framework like devise, for example devise ;-) for authentication: Plataformatec: devise Working with JavaScript in Rails Authentication /Login &amp;amp; Logout For hand rolled variant: Add a user model and set it up with encrypted password Add Sessions, Login and Logout to your application Restrict Access to Some Pages Again, see the example project for clarification on what to do.</description></item></channel></rss>