<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Informatics 1 WS 2015/16 on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2015/info1/</link><description>Recent content in Informatics 1 WS 2015/16 on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2015/info1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Info1 - Code Examples Overview</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2015/info1/code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2015/info1/code/</guid><description>Lecture Code Examples Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about noting down any code changes I make in class - I will upload everything here! Thus, the &amp;ldquo;Changes in ws2015&amp;rdquo; links will only work after I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded those changes.
Note that it might also be quite convenient to look at the code on the github page online, the commit history shows you exactly the changes I made. Click on &amp;ldquo;commits&amp;rdquo; and then one individual commit, and you see something like this.</description></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2015/info1/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2015/info1/schedule/</guid><description>Please note that there will be no Info1 classes in the first week due to introductionary things. In the second week, there will also be no lectures and due to a conference - I found no sensible time slot to move our first lab to, so we&amp;rsquo;ll be starting off in the third week.
This schedule is tentative and subject to change!
Week KW Date Lecture Lab 1 41 Tue, 2015-10-13 no class Lab Startup Thu, 2015-10-15 no class 2 42 Tue, 2015-10-20 Introduction to Class &amp;amp; Kara Programming Exercise 01 a Thu, 2015-10-22 Kara Programming: Instructions, Methods, Variables, Loops, Conditionals 3 43 Tue, 2015-10-27 Kara Roundup, Kara and its World as Objects Exercise 01 b Thu, 2015-10-29 Objects, Classes, Methods, BlueJ, Parameters, Compiler 4 44 Tue, 2015-11-03 Class Definitions, Fields, Constructors, Methods, Parameters, Assignment, Getters and Setter Exercise 02 Thu, 2015-11-05 Printing to the command line, Conditional, Local Variables, Expressions 5 45 Tue, 2015-11-10 Abstraction, Modularization, Object Interaction Exercise 03 Thu, 2015-11-12 Object Creation, Object and Class Diagrams, Primitive Types, 6 46 Tue, 2015-11-17 Object Types, Multiple Constructors, Debugger Exercise 04 Thu, 2015-11-19 Collections, Generics, for-each, While Loops 7 47 Tue, 2015-11-24 More Loops, Iterators, Arrays, For Loops, Exercise 05 Thu, 2015-11-26 Library Classes, Reading Class Documentation, Random, Packages, Maps 8 48 Tue, 2015-12-01 Public vs.</description></item></channel></rss>