<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Info3 - Labs and Exercises on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2023/info3/labs/archive/</link><description>Recent content in Info3 - Labs and Exercises on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2023/info3/labs/archive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exercise 01 - Case Studies of Ethical Questions</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2023/info3/labs/archive/lab-01-casestudies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2023/info3/labs/archive/lab-01-casestudies/</guid><description>The German &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Gesellschaft für Informatik&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; published Ethical Guidelines in 1994 that were updated in 2004. They are available online at https://fg-ie.gi.de/ethische-leitlinien.html.
https://fg-ie.gi.de/publikationen/ethische-leitlinien (they haven&amp;rsquo;t read the part about why cool uris dont&amp;rsquo; change: https://www.w3.org/Provider/Style/URI)
We will first have a closer look at the Ethical Guidelines, and then in groups of 3-4 persons you will choose one of the scenarios to read, discuss, and present to the class. Every member of the group will submit their own PDF version with a reflection on the scenario and how the Ethical Guidelines apply to this case.</description></item><item><title>Exercise 01 - Installation Instructions</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2023/info3/labs/archive/lab-01-startup-installation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2023/info3/labs/archive/lab-01-startup-installation/</guid><description>(These are detailled instructions for the installation part of the Info 3 Startup Lab).
Which Computer to use? As most of your colleagues in the former semesters completely ignored the new iMacs in our Web Technology lab and rather unfolded tiny notebooks in front of the 27&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; screens (which unfortunatley even cannot be used as an external monitor), I expect that you will also mainly use your personal computers for working on the exercises.</description></item><item><title>Exercise 01 - Lab Startup</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2023/info3/labs/archive/lab-01-startup-old/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2023/info3/labs/archive/lab-01-startup-old/</guid><description>Nerd Workplace. Foto by slworking2
Pre-Lab (Do this BEFORE the lab) 1. Prepare your work environment lab computers from remote
If you decide to work on your own computer:
[optional] I recomment you work on a Linux or MacOS System. From my experience, setting up Dual Boot Windows/Linux is less troublesome than trying to manage Node.js on Windows. All my instructions will be taylored to Linux and will probably work on MacOS.</description></item></channel></rss>