<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 22:21:30 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/material/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Notes on Learning Python</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/languages/python/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 21:32:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/languages/python/</guid><description>Some Notes and Tips on Getting Started with the Python Programming Language There are many, and many good Python resources available, many of them for free - after all, it&amp;rsquo;s the most frequently used programming language for introductionary courses.
See Python Resources
Suggested Path for info3 As we are already using IntelliJ IDEA: PyCharm Edu comes with a nice interactive Python Course. You can either install/use PyCharm Edu or install the EduTools plugin for PyCharm Professional.</description></item><item><title>Python Resources</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/languages/python-resources/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 18:56:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/languages/python-resources/</guid><description>This is a collection of Python Resources. See Python Notes
The Official Python Documentation 3 Documentation The Python Standard Library — Python 3 documentation The Python Language Reference — Python 3 documentation Python Setup and Usage — Python 3 documentation The Python Tutorial — Python 3 documentation Books Robert Sedgewick, Kevin Wayne, Robert Dondero: Introduction to Programming in Python: An Interdisciplinary Approach. Pearson, 2015 The linked companion website contains excerpts and lots of examples:</description></item><item><title>Learn Python with Tests</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/languages/python/learn-with-tests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/languages/python/learn-with-tests/</guid><description>Links for Learning Python with Tests: The repo: https://github.com/htw-imi-info3/python-learning
The Python Standard Library
The Python Language Reference
Python Unit Tests, list of available assertions in TestCase</description></item></channel></rss>