<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Informatics 1 WS 2019 on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/info1/</link><description>Recent content in Informatics 1 WS 2019 on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/info1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Info 1 - Schedule</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/info1/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/info1/schedule/</guid><description>This schedule is tentative and subject to change.
Week KW Date Part Lecture Lab 1 41 Tue, 2019-10-08 I Introduction to Class Exercise Startup II Introduction to Java, Programming with Kara 2 42 Tue, 2019-10-15 I Introduction to Programming with Kara Exercise 01 II Introduction to Programming with Kara 3 43 Tue, 2019-10-22 I Objects, Classes, Methods, BlueJ, Parameters, Compiler (Chapter 01) Exercise 02 II Class Definitions, Fields, Constructors, Methods, Parameters, Assignment, Getters and Setter (Chapter 02) 4 44 Tue, 2019-10-29 I Printing to the command line, Conditional, Local Variables,Expressions (Chapter 02) Exercise 03 II Abstraction, Modularization, Object Interaction (Chapter 03) 5 45 Tue, 2019-11-05 I Object Creation, Object and Class Diagrams, Primitive Types, Object Types, Multiple Constructors, Debugger (Chapter 03) Exercise 04 II Collections, Generics, for-each, While Loops (Chapter 04) 6 46 Tue, 2019-11-12 I More Loops, Iterators, Arrays, For Loops (Chapter 04) Exercise 05 II Loop Practice 7 47 Tue, 2019-11-19 I Graphical User Interfaces, Lambda Functions (Chapter 13, Chapter 05) Exercise 06 II Lambda Functions, Filter, Map, Reduce (Chapter 05) 8 48 Tue, 2019-11-26 I Library Classes, Reading Class Documentation, Random, Packages, (Hash)Maps (Chapter 06) Exercise 07 II Public vs.</description></item><item><title>Info1 - Code Examples Overview</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/info1/code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2019/info1/code/</guid><description>Lecture Code Examples Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about noting down any code changes I make in class - I will upload everything to github! The &amp;ldquo;Changes in ws2019&amp;rdquo; links will only work after I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded those changes.
Note that it might also be quite convenient to look at the code on the github page online, the commit history shows you the exact changes I made. Click on &amp;ldquo;commits&amp;rdquo; and then one individual commit, and you you&amp;rsquo;ll see the changes.</description></item></channel></rss>