<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Info2 SS2014 - Labs and Exercises on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/</link><description>Recent content in Info2 SS2014 - Labs and Exercises on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Info2: Exercise 00:</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-14/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-14/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Assignment Lab Report / What to turn in Your report is due by 23:00 am the night before your next lab. Submit a Report in PDF Format and the Source Code as Zipped file.
As in Informatics 1, I am more interested in process than in product, although we are now getting more interested in products as well. Your report should include any collaborators on top of the first page, summarize what you learned, and note the time you invested in this exercise.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 01: Dealing with Objects and Toolbox</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-01/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Please bring these exercises P1 and P2 printed out or written out with you to lab. Please have your name on your page.
P1. How do you obtain tickets to go see a movie? Write down the steps that you take, in order.
P2. If you have tickets and have to cancel, what do you have to do? Write down the steps, in order.
P3. Read up on the Class-Responsibility-Collaboration Card method (CRC Cards).</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 02: Implementing CRC Cards</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-02/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Please think through the following questions before coming to the lab. Write down your answers and bring them with you for pre-lab check-in.
This exercise builds on the design you did last week using CRC cards. What properties should a data structure have that can model movie theater seats? Given an n x m matrix and a cell c in (r, c). How do I reference the neighboring cells in the same row?</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 03: Chatterbox</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-03/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Please research the following questions before coming to the lab. Write down your answers and bring them with you for pre-lab check-in. There are many sites that will show you the code for this.
How do you set up a connection between two computers in Java? Write a method to read from a connection in Java. Write a method to write to a connection in Java. Assignment These are the required exercises for this week.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 05: Execution times</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-05/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Please have these completed before coming to the lab. BTW, I like questions like this on the exam&amp;hellip;
Programs A and B are analyzed and are found to have worst-case running times no greater than 150 N log N and N2 , respectively. Answer the following questions, if possible:
Which program has the better guarantee on the running time for large values of N (N &amp;gt; 10 000)?
Which program has the better guarantee on the running time for small values of N (N &amp;lt; 100)?</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 06: Reverse Polish Notation</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-06/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-06/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Make sure that you understand postfix evaluation.
Łukasiewicz was a Polish logician, so his notation for parentheses-free expressions is often called Reverse Polish Notation. To get your brain in gear, convert the following expressions to RPN! What are the values of the expressions?
1. &amp;lt;tt&amp;gt;1 * 2 + 3 &amp;lt;/tt&amp;gt; 2. &amp;lt;tt&amp;gt;1 + 2 * 3 &amp;lt;/tt&amp;gt; 3. &amp;lt;tt&amp;gt;1 + 2 - 3 ^ 4&amp;lt;/tt&amp;gt; 4. &amp;lt;tt&amp;gt;1 ^ 2 - 3 * 4&amp;lt;/tt&amp;gt; 5.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 07: Recursive Triangles</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-07/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-07/</guid><description>Pre-Lab What exactly is an equilateral triangle? Can you write a class that draws a triangle? What data do you need to know in order to put a triangle at a particular position on the screen?
What is the mathematical formula for finding the midpoint of a line segment that connects two Points?
What is the resolution of your computer screen? How can you find out? What is the largest equilateral triangle that you can show on a screen with this resolution?</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 08: Multi-Threaded Chat Application</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-08/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-08/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Experiment with the Source Code Examples for Concurrency.
Do a Class Design for your Chat Application: Don&amp;rsquo;t put all of the Server in one and all of the Client in another class; design small classes with one responsibility and small methods. Especially the user interface should not be intermingled with the rest of the application.
Assignment: Multi-Threaded Chat This builds on Assignment 3, Chatterbox, where you built a little Chat Application that was only able to handle one connection from one client.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 09: Eight Queens</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-09/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-09/</guid><description>Pre-Lab This is one of the standard exercises that all computer science students have to solve at least once in their lifetimes! If you have never played chess, find someone who does or find a book and look up how a Queen moves and threatens in chess. Find out what a chess board looks like. Define a matrix (two-dimensional array) of integers in Java. Write a method to put a -1 in every cell of the matrix.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 10: Probabilistic Algorithms</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-10/</guid><description>Pre-Lab How do you compute the area of a circle and a rectangle? Draw an circle that matches exactly into a square. How do the areas of the circle and the square relate to each other? How can you represent points in a plane? Prepare a sketch with formulas about the ratio of the areas and how to determine if a given point in the square is as well within the circle.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 11: Getting from A to B</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-11/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Define an abstract data type for a weighted graph. What methods does your ADT need? What are the signatures for the operators? Find algorithms for determining the minimum path and the cheapest path between two nodes in a directed graph. I strongly suggest visiting a library (that is one of these places that keeps ancient books around). There are Algorithm and Data Structure books available in many languages. There is also an example in the Wikipedia, but it is not really easy to understand.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 12: Scrabble Cheater - Basic Edition</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-12/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-12/</guid><description>Foto by Mags_cat
Pre-Lab Review the rules of Scrabble, if you have never played it before. What was a permutation? What would a normalization function for different permutations of characters words look like? That is, &amp;ldquo;JAVA&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;VAJA&amp;rdquo; are permutations, what would a normalized permutation look like? How do you determine if two strings are permutations of each other? How can you generate all permutations of the characters in a String?</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 13: Scrabble Cheater - Deluxe</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-13/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-13/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Foto by Piotr
What would the exact data structure be for a hash table that stores Strings and chains the collisions? Review the construction of a hash function. Note that you will need prime numbers. Does your isPrime method work? If not, fix it now. Assignment This week we will improve the Scrabble Cheater by storing the Words in a Hash Map, making the lookup of permutations way more efficient.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Exercise 4: Histogram</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-04/</guid><description>Pre-Lab Please think through the following questions before coming to the lab. Write down your answers and bring them with you for pre-lab check-in.
In some programming languages, such as Ada, you can define an array of characters with any discrete type as the index:
someArray : ARRAY ['A' .. 'Z'] of INTEGER; You can then access the array, for example, using a value of character type: someArray[&amp;lsquo;T&amp;rsquo;]. Java does not have this feature.</description></item><item><title>Info2: Handout for Exercise 6: Infix/Prefix/Postfix</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-06-handout/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2014/info2/labs/lab-06-handout/</guid><description>##Definitions
Infix: The operator is placed between the two operands: 3 + 5
Prefix: The operator is placed before the two operands: + 3 5
Postfix: The operator is placed after the two operands: 3 5 +
##Calculator algorithm
Convert infix to postfix Use stack to evaluate postfix Output top of stack (should be the only element) ##Evaluate postfix algorithm##
Given a sequence of tokens s While s is not empty: Let t = next token.</description></item></channel></rss>