<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Info3 on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/courses/info3/</link><description>Recent content in Info3 on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 12:13:28 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/material/courses/info3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Notes on Learning Python</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/languages/python/python/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 21:32:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/languages/python/python/</guid><description>Some Notes and Tips on Getting Started with the Python Programming Language There are many, and many good Python resources available, many of them for free - after all, it&amp;rsquo;s the most frequently used programming language for introductionary courses.
See Python Resources
Suggested Path for Info3 &amp;amp; Info3 As we are already using IntelliJ IDEA, using the Python Flavour of IntelliJ IDEA called &amp;ldquo;PyCharm&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t have that steep of a learning curve.</description></item><item><title>Videos Software Engineering</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/bibliographies/se_videos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/bibliographies/se_videos/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About Mermaid</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/mermaid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/mermaid/</guid><description>Mermaid renders diagrams from simple markdown code. It can be used
via integrating the available js library (yarn add mermaid), online via Mermaid-Live, is available in Github markdown files (and others) and can be easily integrated into hugo1 Here are some examples taken from Mermaid Live:
stateDiagram-v2 [*] --> Still Still --> [*] Still --> Moving Moving --> Still Moving --> Crash Crash --> [*] flowchart TD A[Christmas] --&amp;gt;|Get money| B(Go shopping) B --&amp;gt; C{Let me think} C --&amp;gt;|One| D[Laptop] C --&amp;gt;|Two| E[iPhone] C --&amp;gt;|Three| F[fa:fa-car Car] flowchart TD A[Christmas] -->|Get money| B(Go shopping) B --> C{Let me think} C -->|One| D[Laptop] C -->|Two| E[iPhone] C -->|Three| F[fa:fa-car Car] stateDiagram-v2 [*] --> Still Still --> [*] Still --> Moving Moving --> Still Moving --> Crash Crash --> [*] Flowchart Cheatsheet flowchart TD A[Start] --> B{Is it?</description></item><item><title>GIT Intro</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/git-intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/git-intro/</guid><description>Source Code Management mit GIT Für Info2 hatte ich im letzten Semester eine GIT-Introduction aufgenomen:
(Zugänglich mit HTW-Login)
Part 1 - Basics and a simple git workflow: Repository anlegen, commit, push, pull, clone Part 2 - committing the right files: git status, git add, index Part 3 - Stolpersteine: andere machen Änderungen! - merge conflicts, vi als editor Part 4 - Adding SSH Keys and copying Repos from Github to Gitlab Seither habe ich gelernt, dass die Beispiele meiner commit messages nicht gut gewählt waren.</description></item><item><title>Learn Python with Tests</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/languages/python/learn-with-tests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/languages/python/learn-with-tests/</guid><description>I often recommend to write a suite of (automatic) tests to explore a programming language and compile your own &amp;ldquo;cheat sheet&amp;rdquo; for the language.
By keeping the test suite &amp;ldquo;green&amp;rdquo;, you can be sure that everything you see in the source code is actually working.
I drew this idea from two sources: Jim Weirich&amp;rsquo;s Ruby Koans and the recommendation of API Testing by Michael Feathers.
Jim Weirich&amp;rsquo;s Ruby Koans, are a big suite of prepared test cases where you have to fill out the test expectations to learn ruby with a strong emphasis on edge cases - where ruby works in a special way that may not be totally clear or deductible from other programming languages.</description></item><item><title>Python Resources</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/languages/python/python-resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/material/languages/python/python-resources/</guid><description>This is a collection of Python Resources. See Python Notes
The Official Python Documentation 3 Documentation The Python Standard Library — Python 3 documentation The Python Language Reference — Python 3 documentation Python Setup and Usage — Python 3 documentation The Python Tutorial — Python 3 documentation Books Robert Sedgewick, Kevin Wayne, Robert Dondero: Introduction to Programming in Python: An Interdisciplinary Approach. Pearson, 2015 The linked companion website contains excerpts and lots of examples:</description></item></channel></rss>