<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Informatics 1 SoSe 2021 on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2021/info1/</link><description>Recent content in Informatics 1 SoSe 2021 on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2021/info1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Info 1 - Schedule</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2021/info1/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2021/info1/schedule/</guid><description>Week / KW KW Kick Off Date Topic Lab Assignment Material 1 14 Fri 09/04/2021 Introduction to Class &amp;amp; Labs, Chapter 01 - Objects and Classes Exercise 01 - Getting Started and Shapes Source Code, 15 Objects, Classes, Methods, BlueJ, Parameters, Compiler [Video Part 1][101], [2][102] 2 Fri 16/04/2021 Chapter 02 - Understanding Class Definitions Exercise 02 - Ticket Machine Source Code 16 Class Definitions, Fields, Constructors, Methods, Parameters, Assignment, Getters and Setter, Printing to the command line, Conditional, Local Variables, Expressions [Video Part 1][201], [2][202], [3][203], [4][204], [5][205], [6][206], [7][207], [8][208], [9][209] 3 Fri 23/04/2021 Chapter 03 - Object Interaction Exercise 03 - Book Exercise Source Code 17 Abstraction, Modularization, Object Interaction, Object Creation, Object and Class Diagrams, Primitive Types, Object Types, Multiple Constructors, Debugger [Video Part 1][301], [2][302] 4 Fri 30/04/2021 Chapter 04 - Grouping Objects Exercise 04 - Rock Around the Clock - Part 1 Source Code 18 Collections, Generics, for-each, While Loops, More Loops, Iterators, Arrays, For Loops [Video Part 1][401], [2][402], [3][403], [4][404], [5][405] 5 Fri 07/05/2021 Chapter 05 - Functional Processing of Collections (Advanced) Exercise 05 - Rock Around the Clock - Part 2 Source Code 19 Lambda Functions, Filter, Map, Reduce [Video Part 1][501], [2][502] 6 Fri 14/05/2021 * Vorlesungsfrei - Chapter 06 - More-Sophisticated Behavior Exercise 06 - A Better Notebook Source Code 20 Library Classes, Reading Class Documentation, Random, Packages, (Hash)Maps, Public vs.</description></item><item><title>Info1 - Class Material Overview</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2021/info1/material/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2021/info1/material/</guid><description>Video Overview Chapter Link Length Time Sum 1 2 Part 9 Variables [9][209] 20 3 [Part 1][301] Exercise Overview {% include classes/ss2021/info1/references.md %}
Chapter 01 Exercise 1.1 - 1.3 1.30 - 1.35 Prelab Lab 01</description></item><item><title>Info1 - Code Examples Overview</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2021/info1/code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2021/info1/code/</guid><description>Lecture Code Examples Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about noting down any code changes I make in class - I will upload everything to github! The &amp;ldquo;Changes in ss2021&amp;rdquo; links will only work after I&amp;rsquo;ve uploaded those changes.
Note that it might also be quite convenient to look at the code on the github page online, the commit history shows you the exact changes I made. Click on &amp;ldquo;commits&amp;rdquo; and then one individual commit, and you you&amp;rsquo;ll see the changes.</description></item><item><title>Info1 Notebooks</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2021/info1/notebook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2021/info1/notebook/</guid><description>Notebook: Chapter Summaries and Exercises We will provide Paper Worksheets for each Chapter and encourage you to print them out and work on them with real pens.
They will be provided in a format that allows you to bind them as a book later if you wish to.
See Frau Schimpf: DIY: Buchbinden – Offene Fadenheftung for an easy german instruction how this might be done, or How to Make a Sketchbook | DIY Coptic Stitch Bookbinding Tutorial | Sea Lemon for an english one which also shows a different way to attach the cover.</description></item></channel></rss>