<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>B9 Networks WS 2021/22 - Labs on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/networks/labs/</link><description>Recent content in B9 Networks WS 2021/22 - Labs on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/networks/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lab 00 - Intro</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/networks/labs/lab00_intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/networks/labs/lab00_intro/</guid><description>** update 21.10.2021: nur bis 1c bearbeiten, so weit wie Sie im lab gekommen sind.**
Part 1: Playing with Web Servers As the Web and Web applications are a central part of networked applications, we will use the time before really getting started to play around with basic web servers.
You should be able to do most or all of this with your own computers. We will build Teams during the first lab, but feel free to start working on the exercises</description></item><item><title>Lab 01 - Nginx &amp; HTTP</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/networks/labs/lab01_ch01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/networks/labs/lab01_ch01/</guid><description>Part 1: Set up a Real Web Server on a Virtual Machine We will do this part together in lab, where I will provide each group with a virtual server hosted at the HTW - you will install and configure nginx on port 80 on these machines.
Linux / Shell Resources Here&amp;rsquo;s the link to the very brief intro I wrote: Setting up a Debian Webserver This is my recommendation for an introductionary book: LinuxCommand.</description></item><item><title>Lab 02 - Application Layer</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/networks/labs/lab02_ch02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ws2021/networks/labs/lab02_ch02/</guid><description>This lab summarizes all assignments related to chapter 2 - we will be working on Part 1 + 2 during the lectures, work on your own on Part 3. The Labs - every Wednesday at 17:30 - are open to both Groups, for all questions.
You need to include all parts in your lab report for this assignment.
Part 1: email and http Receiving HTTP (P12) Write or find a simple TCP program for a server that accepts lines of input from a client and prints the lines onto the server&amp;rsquo;s standard output.</description></item></channel></rss>