<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Info3/SS2013 - Assignments on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2013/info3/assignments/</link><description>Recent content in Info3/SS2013 - Assignments on Prof. Dr. Barne Kleinen</description><generator>Hugo 0.125.2</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2013/info3/assignments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Assignment 02 - Use Cases and Class Diagrams</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2013/info3/assignments/assignment-02/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2013/info3/assignments/assignment-02/</guid><description>In this exercise you will create a description, develop a detailed Scenario for a Use Case, and draw a Class Diagram for your Web Application. First, write a detailed description what your application should do (in English or German, as you like) as the[one for the HorseTravelWorld in the old exercise][1]. Then, pick the most important (or interesting) use case. For HTW, that might be the Use Case of a User booking a trip, or of a user browsing for trips, or of a user contributing a review.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 03 - Gilded Rose Patterns and Sequence Diagrams</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2013/info3/assignments/assignment-03/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2013/info3/assignments/assignment-03/</guid><description>Reading Assignment for Friday, May 3rd 2013: For this week&amp;rsquo;s lecture and especially the exercise, you will need some knowledge about sequence diagrams, and the Patterns Strategy, Factory, Factory method, Abstract Factory and Template Method.
Here are some good sources:
Sequence Diagrams: Sample Chapter from Fowler&amp;rsquo;s UML distilled: https://www.informit.com/articles/article.aspx?p=169507&amp;amp;seqNum=2 - Please read the full chapter. Strategy Pattern: - make sure you understand the pattern. Template Method: we talked about that in class (Sandy Metz Ruby example!</description></item><item><title>Assignment 05: Functionality and Libraries</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2013/info3/assignments/assignment-05/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2013/info3/assignments/assignment-05/</guid><description>In this assignment, you will add some functionality to your rails app and try out a couple of the principles and practices we covered in the lectures. For this, you need to add some functionality that you can choose yourself. Read through the whole assignment and decide on the functionality you want to add before starting to implement it. It does not have to be the most important functionality of your app – the goal here is to try out the different aspects of rails.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 1: Testing</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2013/info3/assignments/assignment-01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2013/info3/assignments/assignment-01/</guid><description>A. Test Driven Development Create a new Java Project in Eclipse (or your preferred IDE).
Source Code for this Assignment: (removed)
Create a Class Node as in Node.java _as Head of a linked list (added 5.4.13) _and develop a method for deleting Nodes in a List test driven, that is, develop the Unit Tests first, as we did in class. Choose one of the two methods we discussed in class to help the assertions - creating a test helper method as in assert.</description></item><item><title>Assignment 4: First Rails Steps</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2013/info3/assignments/assignment-04/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2013/info3/assignments/assignment-04/</guid><description>In this exercise, you will create a rails application for the first one or two features / user stories of your application. Pick one simple thing that you can solve mainly with the provided CRUD (Create Read Update Delete) features of a rails scaffold using just one or two model classes. If the first things seems to simple for that, add a second – but the goal is really to implement just a little bit of functionality in this first step and mainly set up the whole rails app together with Continuous Integration – we will add Continuous Deployment in the next exercise.</description></item><item><title>Preparation for Week 3</title><link>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2013/info3/assignments/preparation-for-week-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bkleinen.github.io/classes/ss2013/info3/assignments/preparation-for-week-3/</guid><description>This week and in Exercise 2, we will start working on the web applications. Please use the time till Friday to gather some ideas about which web application you might want to develop! We will have a topic collection, discussion and decision in class on friday. Here are my current ideas, just for inspiration:
DailyTasks: An application where a user can make a list of daily tasks (e.g. study English, cleaning kitchen, exercise) and check them off every day.</description></item></channel></rss>